好了  卡塞尔家的女士们
All right, ladies of the Castle household,
提醒一下  你们的圣诞诗篇
just a reminder that your portion for the holiday poem
要在72小时内完成
is due in less than 72 hours.
我只差润色了
I just have to do a polish.
等不及了  你的呢
I can't wait to see it. How's yours coming along?
准备好在卡塞尔家
Are you ready for your big debut
圣诞贺卡上首次亮相了吗
in the Castle family Christmas card?
当然了
Yeah, absolutely.
今年会是最棒的一年
It's gonna be the best year ever!
是啊
Yeah.
好激动
Excited!
同志们  我完全忘了
You guys, I completely forgot.
他说不是大事的
He said that it wasn't a big deal,
但我觉得好像是件大事
but I think it actually kind of is.
是相当大的事
It's a very big deal.
我们甚至会产生攀比心
We even get a little competitive.
我7月份就开始研究我的了
I started working on mine in July.
什么
Wh--
-欢迎加入我们家  -是啊
- Welcome to the family. - Yeah.
我要做什么来着
So what do I have to do again?
写六句风趣  辛辣又意味深长的句子
Write six funny, poignant, eloquent lines
描述过去一年中你的精彩时刻
describing highlights of the past year for you.
-简单  -还得押韵
- Oh. Yeah. - And they must rhyme.
没错
Yeah.
"我完蛋了"跟什么押韵
What word rhymes with "I'm screwed"?
我就是不太擅长押韵什么的
It's just that rhyming isn't exactly my thing.
你可是没去舞会
This coming from a woman who skipped prom
而去参加诗歌比赛的人
to crash a poetry slam?
是朗诵  卡塞尔
Spoken word, Castle.
完全不是一码事
That's a totally different jam.
我可以给你写个俳句
I mean, I could write a haiku for you instead.
-这有违规则  -你还在乎起规矩来了
- Nah, that's against the rules. - Since when do you follow rules?
因为那是我的规矩
Since I'm the one who made them.
等我们去参加分局圣诞派对的时候
You should probably get me your first draft
你就把初稿给我看看吧
by the time we get to the, uh, precinct holiday party.
只剩两天了
That's two days away.
瞧  时间足够了
See? Plenty of time.
准备迎接一起有节日气氛的凶杀案吧
So get ready for a murder with a little holiday spirit.
大概晚10:30发生
Went down around 10:30 p.m.
目击证人看到一辆黑色野马  无牌照
Witnesses saw a black mustang, no plates,
追逐此人
chasing after this guy.
驾车枪杀案吗
This was a drive-by?
但他看上去是近距离开枪致死
But he looks like he was shot close range.
没错  枪手射击头部  确保他活不过来
Yeah, and the shooter capped him in the head to finish him off.
那么就不是随机杀人
So this wasn't random.
有人看到袭击者了吗
Did anyone get a good look at the assailant?
是的  他飞驰而过的时候看到的
Yeah, when he drove by like a bat out of hell.
毛绒绒的红帽子  白色的大胡子
Fuzzy red hat, big white beard.
不是吧  凶手是个圣诞老人
Seriously, our killer is Santa Claus?
三名目击者口供一致
Three witnesses all told the same story.
伙计们  爬下无数烟囱
Guys. Squeezing down countless chimneys?
一晚为上百万人递送礼物
Delivering millions of presents in one night?
这不可避免
It's bound to happen.
圣诞老人终于崩溃了
Santa finally cracked.
或者
Or...
被害人是个坏孩子  不是乖孩子
Our victim was naughty instead of nice.
这太没品了
That's tasteless.
或者凶手穿了圣诞老人的服装
Or a killer just wore a santa suit
因为这是这个时候最棒的伪装
because that was the perfect disguise at this time of year.
我们对被害人有什么了解
So what do we know about the victim?
他名叫埃里克·梅瑟  住在市中心
His name is Eric Mercer. Lives in midtown.
他的医院证件表明他是圣西蒙医院的急诊室医生
His hospital I.D. says he's an E.R. doctor at St. Simon's.
-知道他是从哪过来的吗  -还不知道
- Do we know where he was coming from? - Not yet,
但是他在六个街区外的
but he bought a latte at a coffee shop
一家咖啡店买过拿铁
six blocks away from here
随后才被持枪圣诞老人追赶
before our gun-toting St. Nick came after him.
咖啡师说
And the barista there said that
梅瑟当时背着蓝色背包
Mercer was carrying a blue backpack.
但看到梅瑟逃跑的人
But witnesses who saw Mercer running
称他没带背包
said there wasn't any backpack.
好吧  我们搜索从这里到咖啡店的区域
Okay, let's set up a search from here to that coffee shop.
背包里可能有他被杀原因的线索
That backpack may contain clues as to why he was killed.
或许梅瑟生前最后跟他说话的人
Well, maybe the last person that Mercer talked to
对此会有些见解
can shed some light on that.
他中枪前10分钟
10 minutes before he was shot,
埃里克·梅瑟给圣西蒙医院的一个人打了电话
Eric Mercer called someone at St. Simon's hospital.
是我  我几小时前才跟埃里克说过话
That was me. I just talked to Eric a few hours ago.
对不起  这太让人震惊了
I'm sorry. This is just such a shock.
你们说话时他什么情况
How did he seem when you talked?
有点紧张  似乎很匆忙
A little on edge, I guess... like he was in a hurry.
他有说原因吗
Did he say why?
我以为是因为他叔叔的事
I assume it was his uncle.
他叔叔得了癌症  一个人住
His uncle has cancer and lives alone.
埃里克想去陪伴他
Eric tried to be there for him.
他昨晚也没来上班
He missed work last night, too.
你知道叔叔的名字吗
Do you know his name?
爱德华吧  爱德华·梅瑟
Edward, I think. Edward Mercer.
或许他知道埃里克为什么会出这种事
Maybe he knows why this happened to Eric.
有什么线索
What you got for me, girl?
我在被害人外套胳膊上发现了这个
I found these on the arm of the vic's jacket.
是种小晶体
Some kind of tiny crystals.
他撞碎玻璃窗后跌在了圣诞装饰品上
Could they be from the Christmas decorations that he landed on
会不会是那上面的
after he crashed through the window?
不  这是矿物晶体
No, these are mineral crystals.
希望实验室能分辨出来
Hopefully the lab can I.D. them.
等等  你每次叫我来
Hang on. You always call me down here
都是在实验室出结果后
after the lab results are in,
所以我认为
which leads me to believe that you may have
你还有别的动机
some ulterior motives.
哈维  我有事想要你帮忙
Javi, I want to ask a little favor.
你尽管说
Anything you need.
我父母几乎从不离开路易斯安那州
So...My parents barely ever leave Louisiana,
他们明天要飞巴黎
and they're flying out to Paris tomorrow,
他们临时要在纽约中转
and they have a last-minute layover in New York.
他们想一起见个面
They want us all to get together.
那么是要...
So it's, uh,
见家长吗
meet the parents?
你能行吗
Are you okay with that?
当然
Yeah.
当然  有什么不行的
Yeah. Why wouldn't I be?
这都不算帮忙  这只是更进一步
That's not even really a favor. That's just me stepping up.
其实  我还没说到要你帮忙的
See, I didn't get to the favor part...
部分呢
...yet.
什么
What?
刚刚不是吗
You didn't?
是这样
See, um...
我父母
My parents...
我父母以为我们订婚了
My... my parents kind of think we're engaged.
为什么呢
Wh-why do they think that?
因为我们分分合合
Well, you and I were on again, off again,
他们特别担心
and they just got so worried about
他们的未婚女儿
their unmarried daughter that...
所以你就跟他们说我们订婚了吗
So you told them we got engaged?
我不是有意的  就那么冲口而出了
I didn't mean to. It just...Popped out.
这种事怎么能冲口而出啊
How does something like that just pop out?
我只想让他们别再纠缠下去
I wanted them to stop bugging me.
抱歉  哈维  既然我都说了
I'm sorry, Javi, but once I said it,
也改不了了   现在他们就来了
there it was, and now here they are.
那么你是叫我第一次见你父母
So the first time I meet your parents,
就对他们撒谎
you're asking me to lie to them?
我也要撒谎  但我早就这样了
I'll be lying to them, too, but I've been doing it longer.
我能
Uh... can I...just...
带他们来警局跟你打声招呼吗
bring 'em down to the precinct to say hello?
你就伪装十分钟
And you could just pretend for 10 minutes.
我会让你值当的
I'll make it worth your while.
嗯  没问题  我能做到
Y-yeah, yeah. I-I can do that.
我们已经查看了埃里克家史
So we looked into Eric's family history,
他电话和电脑里的联系人
contacts in his phone and computer.
他没有一个叫爱德华·梅瑟的叔叔
He does not have an uncle named Edward Mercer.
事实上  他没有叔叔
In fact, he doesn't have an uncle at all.
那他为何没去上班  他去哪了
Then why did he miss his shift, and where did he go?
我可能知道答案
I may have an answer to that.
记录显示埃里克
It turns out that Eric
今晚用拼车软件搭便车
used the Hytch Ride Share App to catch a ride
去了皇后区的某个地方
to an address in Queens tonight.
就在他被杀的几小时前
A couple of hours before he was killed.
实际上  他多次去过那个地方
In fact, he took numerous trips to that same address
并都和他医院翘班的时间吻合
which line up with shifts that he missed at the hospital.
那地方有什么
And what's at this location?
显然没有爱德华叔叔
Certainly not uncle edward.
是一个办公大楼
Offices. It's an office building
归纽约常青树卫生公司所有
owned by Evergreen Sanitation N.Y.C.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
纽约常青树卫生公司是已知的
Evergreen Sanitation N.Y.C. is a known front
犯罪集团门面公司
for organized crime.
为什么埃里克·梅瑟要去一个犯罪窝点
Why would Eric Mercer be visiting a mob-owned building?
我们去皇后区查查就知道了
Let's head to Queens and find out.
没门牌  没有名字
No placards, no names.
这地方感觉就像个无人区
It's like this whole place is unoccupied.
埃里克却翘班跑来这里
And yet Eric missed work to come here...
而且是多次来
Repeatedly.
你好  先生  我们是纽约警局的  你能帮忙
Ooh, excuse me, sir, N.Y.P.D. Could you help...
等等  先生  你能帮个忙吗  我们
Wait, sir, could you please just help us? We...
这是个手术室
This is a surgical suite.
归犯罪集团所有
Owned by organized crime.
埃里克·梅瑟不是个普通的医生
Eric Mercer wasn't just a doctor.
他是黑帮天使
He was a mob doctor.
我在集团犯罪组工作了16年
I've worked organized crime 16 years.
认识大部分的角色  但这个人  我不认识
I know most of the players, but this guy? No.
我们推测他可能是纽约常青树卫生公司
Well, we believe that he might have been a family doctor
所有者的家庭医生
for whoever controls Evergreen Sanitation N.Y.C.
我知道  卡鲁齐家族
Yeah, that's the Carlucci family.
自从迪诺·斯卡佩拉掌权后
They've been moving up the Charts
他们的地位就大大提升
since Dino Scarpella took over.
但我不知道他们有个家庭医生
But I didn't know that they had a doctor.
迪诺·斯卡佩拉  我认识他
Whoa. Um, Dino Scarpella... I know that guy.
真的吗
Seriously?
嗯  我为德里克·斯道姆小说做调查时找过他
Yeah, he helped me with research for a Derrick Storm novel,
但他当时就是个中层人物
But back then he was just a mid-level guy.
麦克布莱德警探  假设埃里克就是
Detective McBride, if Eric was a doctor
卡鲁齐家族的医生  你能想到
for the Carlucci family, do you have any idea
他为何被杀吗
why he would have been targeted?
我没听到任何风声  如果你是指这个的话
I haven't heard anything, if that's what you're asking me.
但他被杀的方式
But, uh, the way he was killed,
像是有人想传递信息
sounds like somebody was sending a message.
我们能在哪找到迪诺·斯卡佩拉
Where would we find Dino Scarpella?
他主要的生意都在皇后区
Uh, his main offices are over in Queens.
是一家叫燃情的脱衣舞俱乐部
It's a strip club called Cica Cica Boom Room.
-为什么问这  -我们应该去跟他谈谈
- Why?  - Well, we should go talk to him.
迪诺认识我  他喜欢我
Dino knows me. He likes me.
如果埃里克是黑帮天使的话  他会愿意帮忙的
If Eric was his mob doctor, he'd want to help solve this.
前提是他没有参与其中
Assuming he wasn't involved.
我会让莱恩和埃斯波西托警探
You know, I'll have detectives Ryan and Esposito
与你协调调查野马车和弹道报告
coordinate with you on the mustang and ballistics.
看看能否查到
We'll see if any of that connects
犯罪集团哪个人身上
to anyone in organized crime.
脱衣舞俱乐部之旅
Field trip to a strip club.
卡塞尔  你要再这样看下去
Castle, you keep staring like that,
你至少得消费两杯酒了
you're gonna have to pay for the 2-drink minimum.
抱歉  你刚说什么来着
I'm sorry. What were you saying?
我什么都没说  是你在说
I wasn't saying anything. You were talking.
迪诺的事  说他是个好人
About Dino, about how he's a nice guy
尽管他是个黑帮头目
In spite of the fact that he's a mobster.
-你不会吧  -不是
- Really? - No. But... uh...
我知道你很难相信
I know you find this hard to believe,
但他真是一个很不错的人
but he is a really nice guy.
当然  直到他像杀鱼一样把你宰了
Yeah, sure, up until the point he guts you like a fish.
-里克  真的是你吗  -迪诺
- Rick, is that really you? - Dino!
兄弟  你知道吗
Oh, man. Do you know
我刚读完你的新书  《狂怒希特》
I just finished your book, "Raging heat"?
-真的吗  -太棒了 很赞的故事
- Really? - Terrific. Wonderful story.
-谢谢捧场  -太棒了  真的
- Thank you. - Wonderful, yeah.
是什么风把你吹来了
So what brings you here?
这位美女又是谁
And who is this Venus?
迪诺  这是我老婆
Dino, this is my wife...
凯特·贝克特
Kate Beckett.
纽约警局  贝克特警探
Detective Beckett, N.Y.P.D.
她没什么恶意
Uh, she's... she's okay.
我现在在警局做顾问
I'm actually consulting with the police now,
我们来这想让你帮忙调查一桩谋杀案
and we're here for your help in a murder investigation.
里奇  我乐意给你帮忙
For you, Rick, I'm happy to help.
他们也是
And the boys are, too.
瑞克·卡鲁齐  他是我的首席保镖
Rocco Carlucci... he's my, uh, my chief of security.
这位是克里斯托弗·卡鲁齐
And this is Christopher Carlucci,
-公司事务的副主席  -谁死了
- V.P. Of corporate affairs. - Who got whacked?
埃里克·梅瑟医生
A, uh, Dr. Eric Mercer.
我不认识这个人
Yeah, I do not recognize this person.
斯卡佩拉先生  我们知道梅瑟医生
Mr. Scarpella, we've connected Dr. Mercer
在一间你的机构出资的手术室工作
to a surgical suite paid for by your organization.
迪诺  我们知道埃里克为你工作
Dino, we know Eric worked for you,
但有谁会想杀他呢
But who would want to do this to him?
你能帮帮我们吗
Can you help us out?
很遗憾  我无能为力
Sadly, I have no help to offer.
但请留下来  好好玩玩
But please, stay, enjoy yourselves.
我请客
It's on the house.
斯卡佩拉先生
Uh, Mr. Scarpella...
他说了  我们帮不上忙
Like he said, we got nothing for you.
-喂  埃斯波  -你和卡塞尔在欣赏脱衣舞时
- Hey, Espo.  - So while you and Castle were busy getting lap dances,
莱恩和我却在努力办案
Ryan and I did some real police work.
我们发现了卡鲁齐家族与凶案的联系
We found a Carlucci connection to the murder.
等等  什么联系
Yeah... wait, what kind of a connection?
家族的二号人物
Turns out the family's number two,
克里斯托弗·卡鲁齐有一辆黑色野马
Christopher Carlucci, owns a black mustang.
猜猜里面藏了什么
Guess what was stashed inside.
一件带血迹的圣诞老人服
A santa suit... With blood on it.
克里斯托弗·卡鲁齐
Christopher Carlucci,
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
你为何要杀埃里克·梅瑟
Why did you kill Eric Mercer?
我没有
I didn't.
行  那你给我解释一下
Okay, then why don't you clear this up for me?
案发时你在哪里
Where were you at the time of the murder?
怎么会有人在犯罪现场看到了你的野马
And why did witnesses see your mustang at the crime scene?
我们又怎么会在你的后车箱
And why did we find a santa suit
找到了一套沾有埃里克血迹的圣诞老人衣服
stuffed in the trunk of your car with Eric's blood on it?
听着  克里斯托弗  我并不认为你是某天醒来
Look, Christopher, I don't think you just woke up one morning
突然就决定要杀了家庭医生
and decided to kill the family doctor.
应该是上面下的命令吧
That kind of order comes from above.
是迪诺·斯卡佩拉下的命令吗
Did Dino Scarpella give the order?
我要找律师
I want a lawyer.
搞不懂卡鲁齐家的人为什么要杀了他们的医生
I wonder why the Carluccis would kill their own doctor.
也许他看到了什么不该看的东西
Maybe he saw something he shouldn't have,
或是没能救活某个重要的帮派人物
let the wrong mobster die on his table.
也对
Yeah.
-失陪  -嗯
- Excuse me. - Yeah.
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle.
里克  我们得谈谈
Rick, we need to talk.
他想让你去脱衣舞俱乐部见他
He said he wanted you to meet him at the strip club?
为什么
Why?
他只说事情很紧急
He just said that it was urgent.
要是迪诺·斯卡佩拉发出邀请
And when Dino Scarpella issues an invitation,
你可不能用"不"来答复他
You don't R.S.V.P. with "No."
当然可以  尤其是他可能下令杀了埃里克·梅瑟
Yeah, you do, especially if he put a hit out on Eric Mercer.
他打到分局来找我
He called me at the precinct.
他知道我娶了你
He knows I'm married to you.
我不会有危险的
I-I'm in no danger here.
天啊  卡塞尔  这话听着像墓志铭一样
Oh, God, Castle, this just sounds like an epitaph.
这样吧  我跟你一起去
Um...You know what? I'm gonna go with you.
他说了让我一个人去
He said to come alone.
这次你得相信我
You're gonna have to trust me on this.
迪诺  他是个有操守的人
Dino... He's an honorable man.
好吧  埃里克肯定也是这么想的
Yeah, well, I bet that's what Eric thought, too.
自己去买点好东西  好吗
Buy yourself something nice with it, okay?
别老想着这场悲剧了
Take your mind off this tragedy.
别告诉你母亲  好吗
And don't tell your mother, okay?
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, daddy.
简
Jane.
她花在衣服上的钱
The roll of cash she spends on clothes
都能撑死一匹马了
could choke a horse.
我甚至买下了一家山寨的名牌服饰店
I even bought an imitation couture company,
但假货可配不上我女儿
but the fake stuff isn't good enough for my girl.
对吧  尤其她现在还很伤心
Right? Especially now that she's upset.
她跟埃里克  他们非常亲近
She and Eric -- they were very close,
从小就非常亲近了
very close since they were kids.
那么你承认他是你的医生了
So you're admitting he was your doctor.
我不喜欢"承认"这个词
I don't like that word "Admit."
那就"确认"
"Acknowledging"?
里克  你和我
Wow, Rick, me and you --
我们以前关系不错  对吧
We had a good relationship once, huh?
现在也是啊  不是吗
We still do, don't we?
我不知道
Well, I don't know. I --
我得确认说话不用有顾忌
I need to know I can speak freely.
得确认你不会转身就去对警方
That you're not gonna turn around and repeat
重复我说的话
what I say to the authorities.
迪诺
Dino...
你可以相信我
You can trust me.
埃里克是家人
Eric was family.
是我表亲布鲁诺的孩子
My cousin Bruno's kid,
他跟第三者生的
By a girl he had on the side.
他死在了监狱里
Bruno... he died in the slammer,
于是我一直照看着埃里克
So I looked after Eric.
我送他上最好的学校
I sent him to the best schools.
我不想让他为家族工作  可是...
I didn't want him to work for the family, but...
要想听上帝发笑  你就
If you want to hear god laugh, you tell him --
就把你的计划告诉他  等他作弄你
Tell him all your plans, right?
那么到底发生了什么
So what happened?
几年前
A few years back,
我的一个手下中了枪  这种事时有发生
One of my guys got shot. It happens.
他本来会死的  可埃里克站了出来
He would have croaked, but Eric stepped up.
接下来
Next thing I know...
他就喜欢上了这样的生活
Next thing I know, he's got a taste for the life.
我必须查清楚是谁干的
I need to find out who did this to him.
别误会啊  迪诺
Don't take this the wrong way, Dino,
可我觉得你已经知道是谁了
But I think you already do know.
不是克里斯托弗
It was not Christopher.
-一切证据都表明是他  -他是被陷害的
- All the evidence says that it was. - He was framed.
他是清白的  至少在这件事上是
He's innocent -- when it comes to this, anyway.
我知道  因为我当时跟他在一起
I know... Because I was with him.
迪诺  如果情况属实
Dino, if that's true,
你只要给贝克特打个电话就行
all we have to do is call Beckett.
-你可以做他的不在场证明  -不  不行
- You can alibi him. Mm, no, that's no good.
要知道  当时我跟克里斯托弗
See, at the time, me and Christopher, we were,
我们在进行一项很敏感的商业交易
Uh, engaged in a sensitive business transaction.
你说的"敏感"  是指"非法"吧
And by "Sensitive," You mean "Illegal."
这词我也不喜欢
I don't like that word either.
我的重点是
My point is this --
警察没在追查杀埃里克的真凶
The cops are not looking for Eric's killer
因为他们以为自己已经抓到真凶了
because they think they already got him.
就算他们去找
Even if they are out looking for him,
我的人也不会给乖乖配合
Nobody in my world's gonna give 'em the time of day.
所以就需要你出马了
And this is where you come in.
-我  -对
- Me? - Yeah.
我要你证明克里斯托弗的清白
I need you to prove Christopher's innocence
并找出杀死埃里克的真凶
and find Eric's killer.
你看  与这事相关的人肯定不会跟警察合作
See, nobody connected's gonna talk to the cops,
但如果我替你作保
But if I vouch for you,
给你一些警察得不到的权限
give you access no cop has ever gotten...
迪诺  我不知道自己...
Dino, I don't know if I'm --
我可以开个玩笑  说要给你一份
I could crack a joke about making you an offer
你无法拒绝的邀约
you can't refuse.
但你一定不能拒绝
But you cannot refuse.
明白
Understood.
那就好
Good.
但我如果查出是谁干的
But if I figure out who did this,
你得让我把凶手缉拿归案
you have to let me bring the killer to justice.
我是指上公堂
And by "Justice," I mean legal justice,
不是直接灭了他
not just taking him out.
到时候我要打电话通知贝克特
When the time comes, I need to call Beckett.
我们要用缄默法则起誓
We will swear by the code of silence.
乌黙它
Omerta?
你现在也跟我们血脉相连了  里克
You're blood now, Rick.
你也是我们的家人了
You're family.
别让我失望
Do not let me down.
我整理一下
So let me get this straight.
你想代表你的黑帮老大朋友
You want to reinvestigate Eric's murder
重新调查埃里克的谋杀案
on behalf of your friend dino the mob boss?
好吧  你这么说听起来可挺糟的
Okay, well, when you put it like that, it sounds bad.
不管我怎么说都挺糟的
It sounds bad no matter how I put it.
卡塞尔  我们已经抓到凶手了
Castle, we have the killer.
克里斯托弗当时跟迪诺在一起
Christopher was with Dino at the time.
那只是迪诺说的
According to Dino.
迪诺在耍你
Dino is playing you.
时常有帮派成员被捕
Mobsters get arrested.
这是做生意的成本  迪诺清楚这点
It's a cost of doing business. Dino knows that.
所以克里斯托弗要不是真的清白
So why go through the trouble of asking me to look into it
他为什么还要大费周章请我去调查
unless Christopher was innocent?
首先  他那可不叫"请"
Firstly, he didn't exactly ask you,
其次  他只是想让自己的二把手回到身边
and secondly, he just wants his number two back.
其实不只这些
Well, there's more to it than that.
乌黙它
Omerta.
我们发了血誓
We made the blood oath.
不是我的主意  我也没别的选择
It was not my idea, and I did not have a choice.
你相信迪诺就是因为被他取了点血
So you believe Dino because he gave you a paper cut?
如果我调查埃里克被杀案
Look, if I look into eric's murder
发现凶手还是克里斯托弗·卡鲁齐  那就是他
and the trail leads back to Christopher Carlucci, so be it.
但如果并非如此
But if it doesn't,
难道你不想知道真凶是谁吗
don't you want to know who the real killer is?
好吧
Fine.
但是你得保证不让盖茨警监
But you have to promise that Captain Gates
发现我们在调查
isn't gonna find out that we're poking around
已经结了的案子
an already closed case.
而且  你必须随时向我
And... you have to keep me looped in
-汇报新情况  -我保证
- every step of the way. - I promise.
既然迪诺给了我在家族中任意查访的权利
And since Dino gave me an all-access pass with the family,
我就从克里斯托弗问起吧
I'm gonna start by talking to Christopher.
谢谢
Thank you.
我听说迪诺·斯卡佩拉和卡塞尔见了面
I heard Dino Scarpella and Castle had a sit-down.
你觉得是为什么
What do you think that's about?
不知道
I don't know.
但我讨厌他有事瞒着我们的情况
But I don't like him going around us like this.
嗨  宝贝
Hey, baby!
哈维尔  这是我的父母
Javier, these are my parents--
沃特和梅琳达
Walter and Melinda.
-你好  -好吧
- How you doing? - Ooh, oh. Okay.
我们是喜欢拥抱的教区家庭  孩子
We're huggers in the parish family, son.
不用拘束  叫我爸爸就行
And go ahead. Call me "Dad."
好吧
Oh. Okay.
我终于知道蕾妮
Ooh! I can see where Lanie
美丽的眼睛是从谁儿那遗传来的了
gets her beautiful eyes from.
而且她的医疗头脑肯定是继承了您
And her medical brain must come from you.
我听说您是外科医生
I hear that you're a surgeon.
心胸手术医师  不过已经退休了
Cardiothoracic. But retired.
别提你的老本行了  亲爱的  我只想
No shop talk, dear. The only talk I want
听那个故事
is to hear the story.
-哪个故事  -当然是求婚场面啦
- What story? - The proposal, of course.
那个故事啊  没错
Oh! That story! Right.
哈维
Javi?
那个故事
Yes, the story. Um...
我们
Uh, we, um...
宝贝  你讲的比我好多了
You know, baby, you tell it so much better than me.
不如你来
Why don't you...
这家伙啊  二位真该亲眼看看当时的状况
This guy! You should have seen him.
他带着蕾妮
He rolls Lanie
划船到了中央公园的湖中心
out into the middle of the central park boat pond.
单膝跪地
He gets down on one knee,
紧张的差点把船都弄翻了
so nervous he nearly capsizes the boat.
差点害他俩都掉进水里
Almost sends them both into the water.
当时蕾妮也是这样的表情
That's just what Lanie did when...
因为她看到了戒指
she saw that ring.
完美契合
Perfect fit.
顺便提一下我叫凯文  埃斯波的搭档
I'm Kevin, by the way -- Espo's partner and, you know,
求婚计划我也有份哦
proposal planner-in-crime.
太浪漫了  整个恋爱过程我都要听
That's so romantic. I want to hear all about the courtship.
真希望有那个时间
I just wish we had time for all of that,
但是  我们都有工作
but, you know, with us having to get back to work
而且你们还要赶飞机所以
and -- and you having to catch your plane...
事实上  我刚收到短信
Actually, I just got a text
我们的航班被推迟到明天了
that our flight's been delayed till tomorrow.
所以不如待会儿我们一起出去吃个晚饭吧
So why don't we all go out and have dinner a little later?
听起来不错  沃特
Yes, that sounds great, Walter.
我是说  爸爸
I mean... dad.
你确定可以和他谈
You sure he's good?
你问吧  我知道的都会告诉你
Ask your questions. I'll tell you what I know.
谢谢
Thanks.
那么
So...
迪诺说你是被陷害的
Dino says you were set up.
有谁会想陷害你
So who'd want to frame you?
我是他的得力助手
I'm his right-hand man.
我能说出50个等不及想
I know 50 guys who would slit my throat...
干掉我的人
like that.
但他们会直接动手
But they'd kill me.
不会有想陷害我的人
Not one of 'em would frame me.
好吧  那说说埃里克吧
All right, then let's talk about Eric.
埃里克  最近有点担心
Eric, uh, recently had some concerns.
担心有人要杀他吗
Concerns that someone was after him?
也不是
Not exactly. Uh...
埃里克作为我们的医生
See, Eric being our doctor --
这是我们的家族秘密
we kept that secret.
以便他能继续无关家族那部分的生活
You know, so he could have a life outside the family.
但我猜他是担心这个秘密泄露
But I guess he was afraid that his secret got out,
因为几天前  他来找我
because a few days ago, he comes to me
让我帮他个忙
and he asks a favor.
帮什么忙
What kind of a favor?
他想要手机窃听检测器
He wanted phone tap detectors.
追踪设备
You know, tracing equipment.
他觉得自己在被监视
He thought he was being watched.
-谁在监视他  -我不知道
- By whom? - I don't know.
那时我以为他只是太多疑了
You know, at the time, I thought he was just being paranoid.
但我为了以防万一  所以
But I wanted to be safe, so, I, uh,
还是帮他联系了网络高手丽塔
I hooked him up with cyber Rita.
你们几个白痴准备好了吗
Are you morons ready?
我要切断警报器了  3  2  1
I'm cutting the alarm in 3, 2, 1...
结束
bam!
是  我帮了医生
Yeah, I helped the doc.
埃里克有告诉你他觉得是谁在监视他吗
Well, did Eric tell you who he thought was watching him?
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
他问你要反追踪设备时
When he asked for the counter surveillance equipment.
他问我要的不是那个
That's not what he asked me for.
不是吗
It isn't?
不  克里斯托弗打给我说埃里克要什么
No. Christopher called me and told me to give Eric
就给什么  所以我就给了
whatever he needed, so I did.
埃里克要的是什么
And what did Eric need?
听起来好像是
Well, it sounds like
埃里克跟我和克里斯托弗说的不一样呢
Eric told Christopher one thing, and me another.
所以在我确保这位打手大哥
So I'm not gonna say another word
不会把我丢进河里喂鱼前
until I'm sure that lurch over there
我不打算再说什么了
isn't gonna have me sleeping with the fishes.
打手  你能不能
Uh, lurch, would you --
我是说  瑞克  你能不能
Rocco, I mean, could you --
他想要烫手信用卡
He wanted hot credit cards.
失窃信用卡  为什么呢
Stolen credit cards? What for?
为了不花自己的钱买东西
So he could buy things and not have to pay for them.
-谢谢  这...  -我给了他一打
- Thank you. That's -- - I gave him a dozen,
每张刷爆前差不多
So each is good for about 2 grand
能刷两千
before it needs to be tossed.
埃里克有没有说为什么需要两万四千美金
Did Eric say why he needed $24,000?
也许是为了租车
Maybe for wheels?
他问我说这卡能不能
He asked if he could use the card to access
用在刷卡付钱的租车行  但我跟他说
a swipe-and-go car rental, but I told him
要在租车行用一定要再办张假身份证才行
he was definitely gonna need a fake I.D. to go with the card.
你能把那些信用卡号给我发到邮箱里吗
Okay, could you e-mail me those credit card numbers
-以便我检查一下他有没有用  -好
- so I can see if he used them? - Yeah.
你们哪个白痴碰响了防盗门
Which of you idiots just triggered the security door?
失窃信用卡  可能还有逃亡用车
Stolen credit cards, a possible getaway car.
听起来埃里克好像是要跑路啊
Sounds like eric was about to go on the run.
只是被凶手抢了先
Only the killer got to him first.
如果不是克里斯托弗杀的  那凶手是谁
Okay, so if Christopher didn't kill him, then who did?
也许埃里克用卡买的东西能提供一些线索
Maybe whatever Eric was charging on those cards could give us a lead.
不幸的是  信用卡这条线没戏
Unfortunately, cards are a bust.
我查了所有的卡号  最近都没有被使用
I ran the numbers. No recent activity.
-我们找到这些卡了吗  -没
- Did we ever find those cards? - Uh, no.
医院的柜子  他的公寓
Not in his hospital locker or his apartment
-他身上都没有  -有可能凶手拿走了
- or on his body. - Maybe the killer took them.
我会让托瑞监控那些信用卡号
Well, I'll have Tory monitor the numbers,
看它们有没有人使用
see if any activity pops.
-我想我有条线索  -我们真的认为
- Think I got a lead. - So we're really thinking
-凶手不是克里斯托弗·卡鲁齐对吗  -他不是
- that this killer is not Christopher Carlucci, right? Yes.
-有可能不是  -不是吗
- Maybe. - No.
算了吧  那家伙有罪
Oh, come on. The guy is guilty.
没人会想到他不是凶手  直到卡塞尔
Nobody thought otherwise until Castle over here
开始兼职给那伙人打工
started moonlighting for the mob.
我觉得你说的有点过了
I think that might be overstating it a little.
你和他们歃血为盟了都
You took a blood oath.
你让他们把你变成了个名誉匪徒
You let them turn you into an honorary mobster.
-你怎么回事  -行了吧  哥们
- What's wrong with you? - Oh, come on, man.
有多少黑手党以外的人
How many people outside of the mafia
能有机会以沉默法则宣誓
ever get to swear Omertà?
我觉得这是一次人生的难以忘怀的经历
I think it is a... experience of a lifetime.
-你当然这么想  -不是说你有线索吗
- Of course you would. - Didn't you say you had a lead?
实验室识别出了蕾妮在埃里克袖子上
Yeah. The lab was able to identify the crystals
找到的晶体是什么
that Lanie found on Eric's sleeves.
那是由亚铁氰化钠
They're made up of sodium ferrocyanide
和氯化钠混合而成的  也就是说
mixed with sodium chloride, which means --
那是道路用盐  可好几周都没下过雪了
It's road salt. It hasn't snowed in weeks.
那为什么埃里克要忙于这件事呢
So why would Eric be literally up to his elbows in salt?
我也不清楚  但岛上只有四个盐仓
I don't know. But there are only four salt depots
其中一个恰好就在犯罪现场
on the island, and one of them happens to be
三个街区的范围内
within three blocks of our crime scene.
-那个蓝色背包  -我们找了但没找到
- The blue backpack. But we searched for it. - We never found it.
那是因为埃里克死前把包藏起来了
That's because just before Eric died, he hid that bag.
那个盐仓
The salt depot.
天  我们跟随线索找到各种地方
Man, the places we go to follow a lead.
但如果这帮我们找到凶手  也是值得的
But if it points to our killer, it's worth it indeed.
你要是想借此帮我写诗
If that's you trying to help me with my poem,
那可是一点用都没有
then it's not working.
就在这
Right over here.
这就是埃里克进入仓库的地方
This is where Eric gained access.
等一下  那是  就在那
Wait, is that the, uh -- right there.
被害人的蓝色背包  你说得对
The victim's blue backpack. You were right.
埃里克肯定是在被杀害前把它藏在这里
Eric must have stashed it here before he was killed.
但他想把什么藏起来
But what was he trying to hide
不被人发现呢
that he didn't want anyone to find?
血衣吗
Bloody clothes?
带着弹孔
With bullet holes.
我能知道就是
Here's what I can tell you.
穿这衣服的人
the guy who wore these clothes
有六英尺高  大概重180到200磅
was about 6 feet, maybe 180, 200 pounds.
-他的伤势呢  -背后中了两枪
- What about his injuries? Two shots to the back.
两颗子弹都射穿了身体
Both bullets exited the front of his body.
根据他被枪射中的部位和出血量
Based on where he was hit and the amount of blood,
他可能已经死了
he probably didn't survive.
有没有尸体上面有这种类型的伤口
So did any stiffs come in with those kinds of wounds?
-当然了  要去除衣服  -我查过了  没有
- Minus his clothes, of course. - No. I already checked.
你能推测出他是什么时候被击中的吗
Can you tell when he was shot?
从血液凝固上看应该是过去的两天内
Blood coagulation says it was within the last two days.
埃里克两天前没去上班  他的拼车软件显示
Eric missed work two days ago, and his hytch app showed
他去了皇后区的手术室
that he went to that surgical suite in Queens.
所以有可能是他的一个黑帮病人
So then maybe this was one of his mob patients.
他不是  至少根据迪诺所说的来看
He wasn't -- at least not according to Dino.
家族里没有人被枪击
No recent gunshot wounds in the family,
在过去的一周里埃里克没有给人治疗过
And Eric hadn't treated anyone in the past week.
那埃里克肯定给其他人治疗过
Then Eric must have treated someone else,
某个和卡鲁齐家族无关的人
someone not connected to the Carluccis.
这是否就意味着埃里克
Could that mean that Eric operated
给其他黑帮家族的人动过手术
on someone from another family?
如果是的话  有黑帮成员死亡或者失踪
If he did, and said mobster is dead or missing,
那麦克布莱德探长应该会知道
then perhaps Detective McBride has heard about it.
同时  我会查一下DNA看血液是否
Meantime, I'll run D.N.A. to see if this blood
和系统上的人有匹配
matches anyone in the system.
谢谢  蕾妮
Thanks, Lanie.
那今晚有什么计划
Hey, hey. Hey. So what's the game plan
在吃饭的时候能应付得了你爸妈
to survive dinner with your parents?
我不知道  我们连五分钟都应付不了
I don't know. We barely survived five minutes with them.
你
You...
万一他们问我们想住在哪儿
What if they ask us where we want to live?
什么时候要孩子怎么办
When we want kids?
他们肯定会看穿我们的  也许我们得坦白
They're gonna see right through us. Maybe we should come clean.
哈维  我不能坦白
Javi, I can't come clean.
如果我坦白了  他们就会没完没了的
If I come clean, I will never hear the end of this.
听着  你已经见过他们  兑现了诺言
Look, you met them. You kept your promise.
晚餐你可以不去
You can skip dinner.
我就说有事情  比如一具死尸
I'll say something came up -- like a dead body.
没门
No way.
我不能变成那种未婚夫
I can't be the kind of fiance that bails
你爸妈难得来一趟我不能爽约
on the one time your parents were in town.
我必须得去  我们订婚了
I have to go. We're engaged.
我们没有
We're not engaged.
但我们有可能订了
But we could be.
将来某一天
Someday.
我不想让他们因为我现在偷偷溜走
And I don't want them to hate me then
而到那时候讨厌我
because I skipped out now.
我问了一下其他的黑帮家族
So I asked around about the other crime families,
查了查看谁失踪了
looked into who might have gone missing
或者你懂的  在过去几天吃了子弹的
or, you know, taken a bullet the last few days.
我想我找到那人了  1米86  86公斤
I think I got your guy. 6'1", 190 pounds.
他能穿上那些衣服
He'd fit in those clothes.
卢卡·泰萨罗
Luca Tessaro?
是泰萨罗黑帮的吗
Of the Tessaro crime family?
是的  他们到处在说
Yeah, and the family's beating the drums
因为卢卡三天前失踪了
because Luca disappeared three days ago.
泰萨罗家族和卡鲁齐家族不是对手吗
Aren't the Tessaros and the Carluccis rivals?
更像是不共戴天的仇人
More like sworn enemies.
这也可能是那位医生被杀的原因
Which could be why things went bad for your doctor.
你不能家族越界
You don't cross family lines.
关于卢卡失踪我们知道些什么
What do we know about Luca's disappearance?
三天前  911接到电话
Well, 3 nights ago, 9-1-1 got reports
说他家附近有人开枪
of shots fired near his neighborhood.
有警员出动  但什么都没找到
Officers responded. They didn't find anything.
但卢卡自那时起就失踪了
But Luca hasn't been seen since.
-谢谢你  警探  -有什么要帮忙的  尽管说
- Thank you, detective. - Whatever you need.
为什么埃里克要给卢卡·泰萨罗治疗呢
Why would Eric treat Luca Tessaro,
一个敌对黑帮的成员
a member of a rival family?
瞧见没  这就是我加入黑帮的魅力所在
See, this is the beauty of me being mobbed up.
暂时地  我可以直接去问迪诺
Temporarily. I can go straight to the source and ask Dino.
卡塞尔  小心一点
Castle, just be careful.
如果埃里克救了卡鲁齐的敌人
If Eric treated a Carlucci enemy,
那迪诺就有杀人的动机
then Dino had motive.
如果这会牵扯上他
Dino is not gonna ask me to investigate
迪诺肯定不会让我继续调查的
If it's gonna lead back to his doorstep.
我肯定能带着答案回来的
But I shall return with answers.
我和他们会去调查
The boys and I will check the area
发生枪击的地方
where those shots were fired.
也许警员漏掉了什么
Maybe officers missed something.
如果警员们遗漏了什么  我也找不到
Well, if unis missed something, I'm not finding it.
五个报警的人都说在这地下通道附近
All five 9-1-1 callers said they heard shots
听到了枪声
near this underpass,
如果卢卡·泰萨罗是在这里被杀的
So if Luca Tessaro was killed here,
那肯定有留下证据
there's got to be evidence.
如果他真的是被害人的话
Assuming he's really our victim.
他肯定是了  蕾妮发短信来了
Oh, he definitely is. Lanie just texted.
卢卡·泰萨罗的资料在系统里
Luca Tessaro's in the system,
衣服上血迹的初步DNA检测结果
and the prelim DNA markers from the bloody clothes
与系统里的相符
are a match.
卢卡和埃里克又是怎么扯上关系的
How did Luca and Eric cross paths in the first place?
伙计们
You guys?
我找到了一个弹头
I found a slug.
叫鉴证科来
Call CSU.
我也有所发现
Hey. I found something else.
来看看这个
Check this out.
这是血迹
That's blood.
瑞克你一定知道不少家族事务的内幕吧
Rocco, you must be privy to the inner workings of the family.
不知是否介意我问几个问题呢
Do you mind if I ask you a few questions?
那  那我就认为你是默认同意了
I'm gonna go ahead and take that as a -- as a "Yes."
那首先  你对埃里克·梅瑟有多了解
So, first of all, how well did you know Eric Mercer?
你还真是不喜欢说话  瑞克
You're a man of few words, Rocco.
真是一句话都不愿说
Very, very few words.
那卢卡·泰萨罗呢
How about Luca Tessaro?
埃里克和他有什么过节吗
Eric have any history with him?
卢卡是个万人嫌
Luca's a sore subject.
万人嫌  为什么
Uh, sore subject, why?
因为他是泰萨罗家族的
Because he's a Tessaro?
因为他是他们家族的败类
Because he's a stain upon his family.
那我想埃里克应该不喜欢他
Okay, I take it Eric didn't like him.
埃里克讨厌卢卡  我们都讨厌他
Eric hated Luca. We all do.
因为他没有好好对简
For what he did to Jane.
迪诺的女儿  她怎么和这有关
Dino's daughter? How is she involved?
某天晚上她在一家俱乐部
One night she's at this club.
卢卡也在  他想对她动手动脚的
Luca was there, and he tried to have his way with her.
消息传到了迪诺那里
Word got back to Dino.
他都准备好杀了卢卡的
He was ready to kill Luca.
他想亲自动手的
Wanted to pull the trigger himself.
-那后来呢  -没  简阻止了他
- Well, did he? - Mnh-mnh. Jane stopped him.
她不想挑起家族之间的战争
She didn't want a war between families.
此外  她也是个非常有分寸的女人
Besides, she's a woman who can take care of herself.
贝克特  我刚发现了非常有意思的线索
Hey, Beckett, I just got some very interesting news.
我也是
Yeah, so did I.
我们在卢卡被枪击的现场发现了血迹
We found blood evidence at the scene where Luca was shot.
继续说
Go on.
一个手镯上沾满了卢卡的血迹
It was Luca's blood on a bracelet.
鉴证科从上面提取的指纹
CSU pulled a thumbprint off of it
与简·斯卡佩拉在车管所备案的相符
that matched a DMV record for Jane Scarpella.
她是迪诺的女儿
She's Dino's daughter.
有可能是简杀了卢卡
Look, it's possible that Jane killed Luca.
她叫埃里克帮她毁尸灭迹随后又杀了他
She got Eric to help cover it up and then she killed him, too.
只不过...我还不知道她的动机
I just -- I don't know what her motive would be.
我想我知道
I think I do.
不错  那快说说吧
Good. Then let's hear it.
不行  得挂了  稍后再打给你说
Can't. I gotta go. I'll call you back and tell you later.
但愿吧
I hope.
头儿现在就要见你
The boss will see you now.
迪诺
Dino.
有什么消息要告诉我吗  里克
What news do you have for me, Rick?
是谁杀了埃里克
Who killed Eric?
你就这么走进来...
You come in here...
到我的地盘上
To my house of business
指控我的女儿犯了不是一起
and accuse my daughter of not one
而是两起谋杀案
but two murders?
并不是...指控的意思...
Not...Accuse as much as....
她大概算是个...嫌疑人吧
Perhaps she's a...Person of interest.
你以为我不懂那是什么意思吗
You think I don't know what that means?
你让我失望了  里克
You disappoint me, Rick.
我请你帮忙
I came to you.
我信任你
I put my faith in you.
我以为我俩之间达成了共识
I thought we had an understanding.
确实有
We did.
真的  你是...
We do. Look, you're the last...
迪诺  你要干...你要干什么
Dino, what are you -- what are you doing?
我绝不容忍谎言  里克
I don't tolerate lies, Rick.
迪诺...
Dino -- eh -- hey...
我们是一家人  记得吗
Hey, we're family, remember?
没错
That's right.
你绝不能不尊重家人
You never disrespect family.
谁不尊重你了
Who disrespects you?
我尊重你  迪诺
I respect you, Dino.
我非常非常尊重你
I-I-I respect the hell out of you.
爸爸  我听说卡塞尔先生
Dad, I heard Mr. Castle
知道杀害埃里克的凶手是谁
had information on Eric's killer.
怎么回事
Oh. What's going on?
先出去  简  我还有正事要办
Step out, Jane. I'm conducting business.
迪诺  你问她  问问她
Dino, ask her. Ask her.
看在以前交情的份上
You at least owe me that much.
如果她是有罪的  你得知道
If she's guilty, you need to know.
不然你也没法保护她
Otherwise, you can't protect her.
有罪  我犯什么罪了
Guilty? Guilty of what?
泰萨罗的死
Of Tessaro's murder.
警方在凶案现场发现了你的手镯
Police found your bracelet where he was shot.
简  你告诉他
Jane, you tell him.
告诉他你不在那里  简
Tell him you weren't there, Jane.
你最好告诉他
You better tell him.
告诉他  简  告诉他
Tell him! Jane, tell him!
老爸  我错了  我是在那里
Daddy, I'm sorry! I was.
可我没有杀他
But I didn't kill him.
我是想救他的
I was trying to save him.
救他
Save him?
爸爸  卢卡和我...
Dad, Luca and I --
我们相爱了
We were in love.
你们什么
You were in what?
在他对你那样之后
After what he did to you?
他对我动手动脚的事情...
That story about him coming on to me --
是我编的
I made it up.
你编的  什么意思  什么叫你编的
Made it up? What do you mean, you made it up?
不然我该怎么说呢
What was I supposed to say?
我和一个泰萨罗家族的人相爱了
That I was in love with a Tessaro?
任何一个家族知道了我们的秘密
If either family knew our secret,
我们就永远无法在一起了
we could never be together.
老爸...
Daddy...
先容我好好想一想
I'm processing this news.
简
Jane, uh...
那晚究竟发生了什么
What happened that night?
卢卡打电话给我的...
Luca called me...
他呼吸十分困难  他被枪击了
Gasping for breath. He'd been shot.
等我找到他时  他已经昏迷不醒了
By the time I got to him, he was unconscious,
快死了
Dying.
他需要我的帮助  我就把他拖进我车里
He needed help, so I dragged him into my car.
大概就是在那时我的手镯掉了
That's probably how I lost my bracelet.
那你就打电话给埃里克了
So you called Eric.
我也不知道该怎么办了
I didn't know what else to do.
埃里克跟我说在手术室等他
Eric told me to meet him at the surgery room.
他为了救卢卡拼尽了全力
He did everything in his power to save Luca,
可是...还是不行
But...He couldn't.
这也解释了埃里克为何被杀
Which explains Eric's murder.
如果泰萨罗家族的人发现埃里克和卢卡的死有关
If the Tessaros found out Eric was involved in Luca's death,
他们肯定会复仇的
they would have retaliated.
他们知道什么  简
What did they know, Jane?
什么都不知道
Nothing.
埃里克处理掉了尸体和衣服
Eric got rid of the body and the clothes
这样他们就不会怀疑到我们家族
So nothing could lead them to our family.
简  卢卡有在电话上跟你说
Jane, did Luca tell you on the phone
谁要置他于死地吗
who shot him, who wanted him dead?
没有  但是上周
No. But last week
他说泰萨罗家族出事了
he said something was up with the Tessaros.
有人要谋权篡位
Somebody was making a power grab,
他要找出那个人
and he was trying to find out who.
我发誓
I swear...
如果埃里克的死和泰萨罗家族有关
if the Tessaros killed my Eric,
我们就开战
we're going to war.
敌对家族的爱情故事
Lovers from rival families.
听起来就像《罗密欧与朱丽叶》
Wow, that sounds like "Romeo and Juliet."
正好埃里克也懂得开药
Right down to Eric as the apothecary.
证实了简的不在场证明
Yo. Jane's alibi checks out.
门卫表示在埃里克被杀时  她在家
Doorman places her at home during Eric's murder.
卢卡·泰萨罗被杀时候
What about the street cams in the area
-周边街道的摄像头呢  -查过了
- around Luca Tessaro's shooting? - We looked.
那条路没有摄像头覆盖
There's no cameras out that way.
也就是说线索又断了
Which means we're dead in the water.
也就是说我没了用处
Which means I could be dead in the water.
如果泰萨罗家族的成员杀了卢卡和埃里克
If one of the Tessaros killed luca and eric,
我们得找出凶手
we need to figure out who it was.
除非你在他们家族也有熟人
Well, unless you got a bud in that family, too,
他们不会开口的
they're not gonna talk.
信用卡方面有线索了
Luckily, a credit card just did the talking.
你们还记得埃里克从丽塔那拿到的信用卡吗
Do you remember those hot numbers that Eric got from Rita?
刚才有人用了其中一张
Well, someone just used one of 'em
-叫了披萨外卖  -是凶手
- to order a pizza for delivery. - It's the killer.
他一定是从埃里克的尸体拿走的
He must have got the cards off Eric's body.
-送去哪  -送到一个瓷砖进口公司
- Delivery to where? - To a tile import business
持有人是卢卡的堂兄  但丁·泰萨罗
owned by Luca's cousin, Dante Tessaro.
随着卢卡的死去  但丁成为了
And with Luca out of the way, Dante becomes
泰萨罗家族的继承人
heir apparent to the Tessaro family.
这家瓷砖公司  在哪里
This tile business -- what's the address?
就是这了
This is it.
再靠近一步就打爆你的头
One more step and I'll blow your heads off.
卢卡·泰萨罗
Luca Tessaro?
你还活着
You're alive?
卢卡  放下武器
Luca, put your weapon down!
为什么  好让你干掉我  回去交差
Why? So you can take me out? Finish the job?
-谁派你来的  -没人派我  泰萨罗先生
- Who sent you? - Nobody sent us, Mr. Tessaro.
我们不会杀了你的
We're not here to kill you.
事实上
No, a-as a matter of fact,
我们以为你死了
we thought you were already dead.
听着  如果你不相信我们
Hey, look, if you don't believe us,
你可以问问简
you can always ask Jane!
是不是  简
Isn't that right, Jane?
等等  没事的卢卡  他们帮得上忙
Wait. It's okay, Luca. They can help.
我们知道我们的家族永远不会同意
We knew our families would never approve of what we had.
所以我们要利用这次机会
So we were gonna use the opportunity
一辈子远走高飞
to leave the life -- for good.
销声匿迹
Disappear.
埃里克身上的信用卡
Those credit cards that Eric got --
是要帮助你们私奔的吗
They were to help you get away?
但当埃里克被杀死
But when Eric got popped,
我想凶手和要杀我的是同一个人
I figured it was the same guy who shot me.
也许他发现我还活着
You know, maybe he found out I was alive
然后跟踪埃里克要杀我灭口
and went after Eric to get to me.
是谁要杀你  卢卡
Who was trying to kill you, Luca?
我没看见他的样子
I didn't see him.
没人见过他  但是
No one ever has, but...
他自称"半影"
he calls himself il Penumbra.
你知道他的事吗
Well, what do you know about him?
他是几个月前新出现的人物
He's a new player who showed up a few months ago.
他开始在我们的地盘和店家联系
He started hitting up store owners on our turf
收取保护费
for protection payments.
那么那些店家一定认得他
Well, then the store owners must know who he is.
他用化名通过电邮管他们要钱
He was reaching out to them anonymously...Through e-mail.
电汇付款否则后果自负
Wire the payment or face consequences.
我们的一个干洗店拒绝付钱给他
One of our dry cleaners refused to pay,
他的干洗店被烧为灰烬了
his store burned down to the ground.
黑手党2.0
Mafia 2.0.
不管这家伙是谁  他要侵占我们的地盘
Whoever this guy is, he was moving into our territory,
家族派我去追踪他
and the family ordered me to track him down.
我发现了那些店主
I uncovered the account
电汇钱给他的那个银行账号
where the shopkeepers were wiring him the money.
之后  我就接到一个人的电话
Next thing I know, I get a call from some guy
说他可以帮我
saying he could help.
他叫你在桥下和他见面
He tells you to meet him under the bridge,
但其实是个圈套
but it's a setup.
我们找店家谈过话证实了卢卡说的
The shopkeepers we talked to confirmed Luca's story.
"半影"已经恐吓他们数月了
This il Penumbra's been terrorizing them for months.
怎么追踪一个没见过的人呢
How do you track someone who nobody's seen?
没法通过卢卡发现的那个银行账户
Not through that bank info that Luca uncovered.
账户追踪到开曼群岛一个私人账户就断了
It dead-ended at a private account in the Cayman islands.
考虑到国际银行法
And given international banking laws,
没有办法找出这开户人
there's no way to determine who owns that account.
也许还有办法
But maybe there is.
我认识一个朋友也许能帮到我们
I, uh, made a new friend who might help us
绕开那些烦人的国际银行法
skirt those pesky international banking laws.
丽塔  我知道这是不情之请
Now, Rita, I know this is a big ask,
但如果我们能查出账户是谁的
but if we can figure out who owns that account,
我们就找出了埃里克的凶手
we'll find Eric's real killer.
这个"半影"
Now is this Penumbra character
和陷害克里斯托弗是同一个人吗
the same guy that framed Christopher?
我们觉得是的
We believe so, yes.
好吧  我帮你
All right, fine, I'll help.
但这是因为我不想圣诞节独守空闺
But only 'cause I don't want to sleep alone on Christmas.
你和克里斯托弗
You and Christopher?
好的
Okay, and...
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
这个化名也太怂了
It's not even a clever alias.
也许这人用那化名
You know, this guy might be using that alias
去取现了
to withdraw his cash,
但我肯定他是远程开户
but I bet he created the account remotely.
你觉得你能到追踪
You think you can trace the account
原先开户的电脑吗
back to the computer it originated from?
我想你应该告诉克里斯托弗
I think you should tell Christopher
新年夜他能回来过夜
he's sleeping over new year's eve, too.
丽塔破解了"半影"的开曼账户
Rita determined il Penumbra's Cayman account
是用市中心图书馆分馆的服务器开户的
was opened using a server at the midtown library branch.
公共终端  这就说得通了
Public terminal. Makes sense.
尤其是大部分的图书馆都没有监控摄像
Especially since most libraries don't have security cameras.
但是对街的便利店有监控摄像
But the convenience store across the street from this one does,
所以我们调取"半影"在当天
so we pulled the video feed from the same day
去开户的监控
that il penumbra created the account.
有时间标记的  因此
It's time-stamped, so...
在这
There.
这是开户之后唯一一个
That's the only person who leaves
几分钟之后离开的人
in the minutes after the account was opened.
你好  圣诞坏人
Well, hello, bad santa.
谢谢你能来见我们  警探
Thanks for coming to see us, detective.
不客气
Of course.
我们在调查中有所发现
Our investigation uncovered something
希望组织犯罪调查科
that we hope the Qrganized Crime Unit
能提供一些线索
might have information about.
你们发现了什么
Uh, what'd you find?
卢卡·泰萨罗还活着
Luca Tessaro -- alive.
你们之前跟我提到过那件血衣
Uh, from the clothes that you told me about,
-我以为他已经死了  -差点就死了
- I assumed that he was dead. - He almost was.
我们相信朝卢卡开枪的人
We believe the person that shot Luca
为了掩盖自己的罪行把埃里克·梅瑟也杀了
also killed Eric Mercer to cover their tracks,
也就是说凶手知道
which means the shooter knew
这两个人有联系
that the two of them were in contact.
凶手称自己为"半影"
The shooter goes by the name of "Il Penumbra".
-听过这名字吗  -没印象
- Does that ring a bell? - Can't say it does.
好吧  这个"半影"
Huh. Okay, well, this, uh, Il Penumbra --
开了一辆类似克里斯托弗·卡鲁齐的野马去犯罪
he planted evidence to frame Christopher Carlucci
并留下证据  企图把埃里克的谋杀案
of Eric's murder after using a mustang like Christopher's
嫁祸给他
to commit the crime.
我不知道你们要说什么
I'm not sure where you're going with this.
你的邻居有一辆黑色野马
Your neighbor owns a black mustang.
他说你那晚塞了点钱给他
He said that you slipped him a little cash
借了他的车
to borrow it for that night.
我们让鉴证组彻底搜索过那辆车
We had C.S.U. sweep the car.
他们在车里的地垫上找到了
They found traces of Eric's blood
你靴子留下的埃里克的血迹
on the floor mat left there by your boot.
你是在指控我谋杀吗
Are you accusing me of murder?
还有卢卡·泰萨罗的谋杀未遂案
Along with the attempted murder of Luca Tessaro
以及勒索重罪
and felony extortion.
我们找到了你在开曼群岛的账户
We found the account in the Caymans.
你在有组织犯罪部门工作了16年
You've been working O.C.U. for 16 years
眼睁睁看着那些不法分子发财
watching bad guys get rich.
于是你决定要黑白都占
So you decided to play both sides,
也分上一杯羹
get a little piece of the action.
这在法庭上是站不住脚的
This will never fly in court.
那我们只有走着看了
Yeah, well, there's only one way to find out.
里克
Rick.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle...
我心怀感激
I'm very grateful.
丽塔也是
And so is Rita.
还有我女儿简  她也让我转达谢意
And my daughter Jane -- she thanks you, too.
她和卢卡接下来会怎样
What's gonna happen to her and Luca?
我决定还是祝福他们
I decided it's better to bless her relationship
并且跟泰萨罗家联姻而不是为此失去自己的孩子
and unite with the Tessaros than to lose my kid.
现在是和平的季节  对吧
'Tis the season of peace, no?
里克
Rick...
你帮了我一个忙
you did me a favor.
我欠你的
I owe you.
你有需要的时候
When the time comes...
随时找我
you call me.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我希望不会有那么一天
That's a call I hope I never have to make.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
晚餐吃得很愉快
Dinner was so great.
我们都等不及再见到你们俩了
We can't wait to see you two lovebirds again.
没准下次咱们可以聊聊婚礼的事
Maybe next time we can talk about the wedding.
再说吧  一步一步来  妈妈
Maybe. One step at a time, mom.
很高兴见到你们
Well, it was great to finally meet you both.
好的
Okay.
-好了  宝贝  -再见  妈妈
- All right, pumpkin. - Bye, mommy.
爱你
Love you.
-你乖乖的  -我会的
- You be good. - I will.
你们一路顺风
All right. You guys have a good trip.
谢谢你
Thank you for that.
实际上这比我想象的
Well, it was actually much easier
要容易得多
than I thought it was gonna be.
但是
But, you know,
这件事让我认真地想了一下咱俩
it made me think seriously about us
和咱俩现在的交往状态
and where we are.
哈维  我觉得这件事还是不要在这谈吧
Javi, I-I don't think we should do this here.
不  我必须得说
No, I have to say this.
蕾妮
Lanie...
跟你假订婚这件事
being fake engaged to you
让我意识到 咱俩在一起有多开心
made me realize how great we are together.
但不是以你父母那种方式
But not the way that your parents are.
或是卡塞尔和贝克特
Or Castle and Beckett
-或是莱恩和珍妮  -我知道
- or Ryan and Jenny. - I know.
我也这么觉得  我
I-I feel it, too. I --
我为你而疯狂
I mean, I'm crazy about you.
我也为你而疯狂  可只是  不是
Oh, I'm crazy about you, too, but just, you know, not --
不是那种方式
not in that way.
而你应该过那样的生活
And you deserve what they have.
我们俩都应该
We both do.
那你怎么跟你父母说啊
What are you gonna tell your parents?
说实话呗  但是等过完节再说
The truth. But after the holidays.
没必要现在毁了他们的假期
No need to spoil their vacation.
所以他用一把仪式匕首割了你的手
So then he cut you with a little ceremonial dagger.
-疼吗  -疼
- Did it hurt? - Yeah, it hurt,
但你不能让他看出来  对吧
but you can't let him know that, right?
-所以我面无表情  -黑手党
- So my face was like a stone. - The Black Hand.
-没错  -是
- Right. - Right.
我能跟你聊两句吗  卡塞尔先生
Can I have a word, Mr. Castle?
当然  拿着
Yeah, of course. Here.
剩下的待会再给我讲
Tell me the rest later.
谁要蛋奶酒
Who wants nog?
有什么问题吗  警监
Is there a problem, captain?
在麦克布莱德警探被转移到县监狱的途中
As he was being transferred to Central Booking,
被不明身份的袭击者
Detective McBride was shot and killed
枪击身亡了
by unknown assailants.
检察官得知在你调查的过程中
The D.A. learned that you were cooperating
曾跟有组织犯罪的成员合作
with members of organized crime in your investigation,
而他们可能会想要麦克布莱德的命
people who might have wanted McBride dead.
这看起来可不妙
Uh...this doesn't look good.
特别是对你
Especially for you.
我很抱歉  卡塞尔先生
I am so sorry, Mr. Castle,
但是检察官上报了市长
but the D.A. spoke to the mayor, and...
市长现在不许你继续跟着纽约警局办案了
you are no longer permitted to work with the N.Y.P.D.
卡塞尔
Castle.
听着  我
Okay, so, I, um...
我把圣诞卡上
I've got my draft
要写的那首诗的初稿写好了
of the poem for the family Christmas card.
想听听吗
Want to hear it?
-好  -好吧
- Yeah. - Okay.
"今年就是一首叙事诗
"This has been an epic year.
生活满载喜悦和泪湿
Life's been full of joy and tears.
破案缉凶
Solving crimes and catching killers,
正如卡塞尔著名的惊悚集
just like Castle's famous thrillers.
我们每天都分享激情
We share a passion every day.
作为伴侣  我们永不分离"
As partners go, we're here to stay."
很棒
It's great.
谢谢
Thank you.
出什么事了吗
Something wrong?
能出什么事  你在我身边呢
What could be wrong? You're here.
好了  大家伙
All right, everybody,
让圣诞树亮起来吧
let's light this baby up!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
今年真漂亮
Looks great this year!